Hasanur Rahman Mohammad

 $London, United \ Kingdom |\ 077538\ 198676\ |\ \underline{rahman.hm2002@gmail.com}\ |\ \underline{www.linkedin.com/in/hasanur-rahman-mohammad}\ |\ https://github.com/ElPatatone$

Personal Profile

I am currently looking for opportunities to further develop my technical skills specifically in data science and working with machine learning models while also gaining experience working in a professional setting. Demonstrably excellent interpersonal skills by working for 3 years as a salesperson in a very high-pressure environment. I am very interested in the implementation of machine learning and deep learning models to solve real world problems, but more specifically how they can be used in robotics. I am a fast learner and am keen to take on new challenges to improve my skills.

Education

UNIVERSITY OF WESTMINSTER | 2021-2024

BSc Computer Science

Activities and Societies: Course Representative, Badminton Club, Programming Society, Gaming Society

UNIVERSITY OF WESTMINSTER | 2020-2021

Foundation year in Data Science and Analytics

Activities and Societies: Course Representative.

NEWHAM SIXTH FORM | 2018-2020

UAL Level 3 Extended Diploma in Art and Design (Merit)

Activities: Badminton Club.

LANGDON ACADEMY | 2013-2018

10 GCSEs including Mathematics (6) and English (7).

Core Skills

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python, Java, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Git, ZSH, Terminal.

SOFT SKILLS

Communication, Teamwork, Adaptability, Independent worker, Problem solving, Creativity.

LANGUAGES

English, Italian, Spanish, Bengali.

Experience

DATA SCIENCE & NLP INTERN | DATA GLACIER | JULY 2022 - PRESENT

- Learning the importance of version control by using git to set up and work on projects given throughout the internship program.
- Will be using Cloud services such as Heroku to deploy and manage some projects that will be assigned later, while also gaining insight into how to scale modern applications if needed.
- A few weeks into the internship various projects will be assigned to complete such as an NLP project about resume extraction and a more advanced one about detecting hate speech using transformers.
- Being exposed to Kanban and Scrum methodologies for delivering business value and improving the software development life cycle.

DATA SCIENCE INTERN | GRIP THE SPARKS FOUNDATION | JUNE 2022

- Working independently on several projects assigned by the mentors. Sample data was given to analyze and manipulate the data to find a solution to the given case study.
- Currently learning more about python libraries to work with the data given such as NumPy, Pandas, SciKit-Learn and Matplotlib.
- Getting access to the machine learning course by Andrew Ng to further improve the theoretical knowledge of machine learning.

DATA ANALYTICS INTERN | GLOBALCERT | MAY 2022

• Getting an overview of the role of a data analyst in a company.

- Understanding how to generate business insights and project proposals to present to stakeholders.
- Learning exploratory data analysis and how to research and gather relevant data to find a solution to the problem statement.

SALES ASSOCIATE | H. SAMUEL | NOVEMBER 2018–2021

- Engaged with a variety of new and regular customers daily in a warm and friendly manner, whilst always providing outstanding customer service.
- Handling customer complaints while being calm and collected while under pressure during busy periods.
- Dealing with finance applications for eligible products using the Hitachi platform.
- Working as part of a team to achieve and often exceed the stores sales target for the period by as much as 15%, allowing us to be on track to make £1 million in sales for the year, £250k per period.
- Maintaining a company set standard of 20% warranty strike rate throughout each sales period.
- Responsible for maintaining a high-quality standard for the watches display section in the shop.
 - o Dealing with watch deliveries and putting the watches in their designated places whether they go out or are reserves.
 - o Routinely cleaning and organizing the watch displays to make sure all our products are ready to be bought by customers.